we need to modify the code we've been
given in this problem
so that it counts up from 1 to 10.
running the code as we've been given it
counts down from 10 to 1.
you can see on line 1 we have a local
variable count initialized to
10 and on lines 3 through 6 we have an
until loop
now an until loop will continue to
iterate
until its condition which you can see to
the right
of until here on line three evaluates to
true this works kind of in the opposite
of a while loop which
iterates until its condition evaluates
as false
so in this code until the local variable
count references 0
the program outputs count and then
decreases the value of count by one
so this code successfully counts down
from ten to one
what we want to do is count from one to
ten
so the first step here is to change our
initial value of count
to one and we know that as we iterate
through this
loop we want to increment count
by one now we need to think hard about
what the condition for our until loop
should be
[Music]
let's first just set it to 10 and see
what the output is
our program only outputs numbers 1
through
and we want 10 to be included in our
output
looking closely at the code you can see
that because we
output the value of count on line 4
prior to incrementing count by 1
when this loop begins its 10th iteration
it will stop
because count will be equal to 10 prior
to ever reaching the code on line 4
and outputting 10. so what we can do to
fix this problem
is continue to iterate into account is
greater than 10.
[Music]
and running in our code you can see that
this will give us the expected output
remember that when you're looping and
keeping track of a count
it's very important to be aware of when
you're performing the desired action
versus when your loop is going to stop
iterating
if we wanted to end our iteration when
count was
equal to exactly 10 we would need to
move our code around a little bit so
that it would still work as we wanted to
so we could increment count prior to
outputting its value
however then our count starts at two
so if we move that code around we have
to remember to also
initialize count to zero
and now again we'll see the expected
output this way
so there's more than one way to write
your code to achieve the expected result
but the important thing is to be very
conscious of
when exactly you make changes to the
values of your variables
and how that's going to affect the
execution of your loop
and here again we know that there are
some ruby methods that
could achieve the same thing that we've
done here with this code
but it's very important to be able to
write this logic out yourself
as there's not always going to be the
perfect method available for what you
want to do
and you may not always have each and
every method memorized at that time